Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and we're going to have some fun today, Marco, right?
我是Catherine，我们今天会玩得很开心，对吧，Marco？
That's right. Today we are taking a small kid and we're going to the park and we're going to play.
没错。今天我们带一个小孩子去公园玩。
Okay, so there are fun things you can do at the park. We're going to learn all about them. Let's take a listen to our dialogue.
好的，公园里有很多好玩的事情。我们要学习这些内容。让我们来听一下对话。
Hey, honey. Where were you?
嘿，亲爱的。你去哪儿了？
I decided to take Kenny to the park and get some fresh air.
我决定带Kenny去公园呼吸点新鲜空气。
How was it? Were there a lot of kids?
怎么样？那里孩子多吗？
It wasn't too crowded, but we had a great time. We got on the seesaw together, then went on a couple of different slides,
不算太挤，但我们玩得很开心。我们一起玩了跷跷板，然后滑了几个不同的滑梯，
and then I tried to go with him in the jungle gym, but I didn't fit.
接着我试着和他一起爬攀爬架，但我挤不进去。
Sounds like fun. When we go, he always just likes to play in the sandbox.
听起来很有趣。我们去的时候，他总是喜欢在沙坑里玩。
Yeah, but today he was really hyper. He even got onto the monkey bars. And then he went on to go on the swings for half an hour. I'm exhausted.
是啊，但今天他特别兴奋。他甚至爬上了猴架。然后他又去荡了半小时秋千。我累坏了。
You should go to the park more often since you don't go to the gym anymore.
既然你都不去健身房了，你应该多去公园。
All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at some of this great playground equipment on Language Takeaway.
好了，我们回来了。现在让我们在“语言要点”环节看看这些很棒的游乐设施。
So, as you said, Marco, today we're focusing in Language Takeaway on some of these things you can do at the park.
所以，正如你所说，Marco，今天我们在“语言要点”中重点介绍一些在公园里可以玩的东西。
Now, the first one is one of my personal favorites from childhood called the seesaw.
第一个是我小时候最喜欢的之一，叫做跷跷板。
The seesaw, that's right. And so basically it's that long piece of, well, sometimes metal or wood, and two people sit at each opposite end.
跷跷板，没错。基本上就是一块长长的，有时是金属或木头，两个人坐在两端。
Yes, and so when one person goes down, the other person goes up. And when that person goes down, the other person goes up. So it's a seesaw.
是的，当一个人下去时，另一个人就上来。当那个人下去时，另一个人又上来。所以这就是跷跷板。
That's right. So yes, it's actually a very common toy that you can play with at the playground.
没错。所以这确实是游乐场里很常见的玩具。
But also another very common one I'm sure everyone knows and has been on is a slide.
但另一个很常见的，我相信大家都知道也玩过的，是滑梯。
A slide. Now this is a bit hard to describe actually. Slides are usually quite colorful.
滑梯。这其实有点难描述。滑梯通常色彩鲜艳。
But they're like tubes that are open and the child can go down. So you're on top, maybe two meters high, and then you go down the slide and you come down to the ground.
但它们像是开放的管道，孩子可以滑下去。你站在大约两米高的顶端，然后滑下滑梯，落到地面。
That's right. And actually it's the noun, a slide, but what you do is, the verb is you actually slide down the slide.
没错。实际上它是名词“滑梯”，但你做的事情，动词是“滑下滑梯”。
Yes, and sometimes you go very fast and it's scary.
是的，有时候滑得很快，很吓人。
That's right. And well, if you want to have something a little bit less scary, you can go into the jungle gym.
没错。嗯，如果你想玩点不那么吓人的，你可以去攀爬架。
All right, jungle. Now the jungle is actually a place. In South America, for example, you have jungles with lots of trees and monkeys and everything.
好的，丛林。丛林实际上是一个地方。比如在南美洲，有丛林，里面有很多树、猴子等等。
But jungle gym is like many, many different metal bars or wood together to make this open structure that boys and girls can climb on.
但攀爬架是由许多不同的金属杆或木头组成的开放结构，孩子们可以爬上去。
So basically you start on the ground and you climb all the way up it.
所以基本上你从地面开始，一直爬到顶。
Okay, so I think this is why it's called a kind of like a jungle gym, right? Because you can climb up and down and grab all these bars.
好的，所以我觉得这就是为什么它叫“丛林攀爬架”，对吧？因为你可以爬上爬下，抓住这些杆子。
You can hang like a monkey from the bars.
你可以像猴子一样挂在杆子上。
Exactly.
没错。
Yeah, so basically it's just a cage that boys and girls can climb on and play with.
是的，所以基本上就是一个笼子，孩子们可以爬上去玩。
Right, and I guess you call it a jungle gym because when you're doing all this, you're doing exercise.
对，我猜叫它“丛林攀爬架”是因为当你做这些动作时，你在锻炼。
That's right.
没错。
All right, so now maybe for the smaller kids who just want to play with some toys, they can just hang out at the sandbox.
好了，现在也许对于只想玩玩具的小孩子来说，他们可以在沙坑里待着。
All right, this is one word, but it's actually quite literal. You'd have sand in a box.
好的，这是一个词，但字面意思很直白。就是一个盒子里装着沙子。
That's right.
没错。
And a sandbox is very safe and very fun because boys and girls can make castles or dig, but there's nothing to it really. It's just a box.
沙坑很安全也很有趣，因为孩子们可以堆城堡或挖洞，但没什么复杂的。就是一个盒子。
It's just a box with sand, literally. Yes, that's right. So that's also fun for the smaller kids to be at the sandbox.
就是一个装沙子的盒子，字面意思。是的，没错。所以对小一点的孩子来说，沙坑也很有趣。
Now, going back to something very similar to the jungle gym, we have the monkey bars.
现在，回到和攀爬架很相似的东西，我们有猴架。
Okay, now monkey bars are a very important part of the park. These are horizontal bars, so they're across.
好的，猴架是公园里很重要的一部分。它们是水平的杆子，横着排列。
And you hang on them with your arms, so your body hangs down. And when you hang, your feet are off the ground.
你用胳膊挂在上面，身体垂下来。当你挂着时，脚离地。
It's very tall.
它很高。
Right.
对。
And you have to move. You have to change from one bar to the other. So it's like a ladder that you're pulling yourself across.
你必须移动。你得从一个杆子换到另一个。所以就像梯子一样，你把自己拉过去。
Yes, exactly. So you've probably seen it exactly how you describe it. It's a ladder, and you just got to hang on to the different bars with your arms.
是的，没错。你可能见过它，就像你描述的那样。它是一个梯子，你只需用胳膊抓住不同的杆子。
It's actually quite difficult to do.
这其实挺难做到的。
I always used to get upset because I couldn't go all the way across because you go from one end to the other end.
我以前总是很沮丧，因为我不能从头到尾爬过去，因为你要从一端到另一端。
But my arms would get so tired that I had to drop down onto the ground.
但我的胳膊会累得不行，只好掉到地上。
Really? All right. Well, something that's a little bit less exhausting but also very fun are when you go on the swings.
真的吗？好吧。嗯，有个没那么累但也很好玩的东西，就是荡秋千。
All right. Swings are great. Now, swings are kind of like chairs, but they don't have a back.
好的。秋千很棒。秋千有点像椅子，但没有靠背。
So you sit down on a piece that's maybe plastic, and someone behind you will push you because you're on these hanging chairs.
你坐在一个可能是塑料的座位上，后面有人推你，因为你在这些悬挂的椅子上。
And they'll push you, and you go forward and backward. And you can go very, very high, and then you come back down.
他们推你，你前后摆动。你可以荡得很高很高，然后再回来。
Exactly. So these are swings. All of this equipment you've most likely seen at any of the parks that are nearby.
没错。这就是秋千。这些设施你很可能在附近的公园里都见过。
But we're going to post some pictures as well so you can see more clearly what they're all about.
但我们也会贴一些图片，这样你可以更清楚地了解它们是什么样子。
Now, let's go and review the dialogue again before we move on to Fluency Builder.
现在，在我们进入“流利度提升”环节之前，让我们再回顾一下对话。
Sounds like fun. When we go, he always just likes to play in the sandbox.
听起来很有趣。我们去的时候，他总是喜欢在沙坑里玩。
Yeah, but today he was really hyper. He even got under the monkey bars. And then he went on to go on the swings for half an hour. I'm exhausted.
是啊，但今天他特别兴奋。他甚至爬到了猴架下面。然后他又去荡了半小时秋千。我累坏了。
You should go to the park more often since you don't go to the gym anymore.
既然你都不去健身房了，你应该多去公园。
All right. We're back. So now let's take a look at three phrases on Fluency Builder.
好了。我们回来了。现在让我们看看“流利度提升”中的三个短语。
So our first phrase today is actually something that the parent is talking about. She wants to take Kenny to the park and get some fresh air.
我们今天的第一个短语是家长在说的。她想带Kenny去公园呼吸点新鲜空气。
Now, what does it mean to go get fresh air?
“去呼吸新鲜空气”是什么意思？
Well, basically, it means to go out and maybe walk or just be outside and get air from the outside.
嗯，基本上就是出去走走，或者只是待在户外，呼吸外面的空气。
Because sometimes you're in your house all the time, and that's not fresh air.
因为有时候你一直待在屋里，那不是新鲜空气。
That's right. So basically, this means exactly what you're saying. It means going outside.
没错。所以基本上就是你所说的意思。就是出去。
So kids often need to go get some fresh air, but also adults do, too.
所以孩子们经常需要去呼吸新鲜空气，但成年人也需要。
Sometimes I feel like when I'm working in the office for a long time, I really need to get some fresh air.
有时候我觉得在办公室工作久了，真的需要呼吸点新鲜空气。
So that means I go outside for a walk.
所以那意味着我出去走走。
Exactly. And you can tell your friends, oh, excuse me for a minute. I'm going to go get some fresh air.
没错。你可以告诉朋友，哦，失陪一下，我去呼吸点新鲜空气。
Or you know what? You're looking a little bit pale. Maybe you should go get some fresh air.
或者你知道吗？你看起来有点苍白。也许你应该去呼吸点新鲜空气。
Exactly. And talking about all this great equipment and how much fun you can have, the wife said, wow, that sounds like fun.
没错。说到这些很棒的设施和能有多好玩，妻子说，哇，听起来很有趣。
Okay. So sounds like fun. It's not actually a sound.
好的。“听起来很有趣”。这其实不是声音。
This phrase is really important because we say it a lot, but it actually just means that it sounds like it will be a fun time.
这个短语很重要，因为我们经常说，但它实际上只是表示听起来会很有趣。
Right.
对。
Or I think it will be fun.
或者我觉得会很有趣。
Yeah. So from what you're telling me, I think it's fun.
是的。所以根据你告诉我的，我觉得很有趣。
That's right. So we can say this about a lot of things. I could say, hey, Marco, we're going to go play some football after work. Do you want to come?
没错。所以我们可以对很多事情这么说。我可以说，嘿，Marco，我们下班后要去踢足球。你想来吗？
Sure. That sounds like fun.
当然。听起来很有趣。
All right. So he thinks it sounds like a good idea. He'll probably come, right?
好的。所以他认为这是个好主意。他可能会来，对吧？
Exactly. So if something sounds like fun. All right. And moving on to our last phrase,
没错。所以如果某事听起来很有趣。好了，继续我们最后一个短语，
we said that it was a great idea that we're going to the park and getting fresh air because we don't go to the gym anymore.
我们说去公园呼吸新鲜空气是个好主意，因为我们都不再去健身房了。
Okay. Now this is a really important phrase to keep as a phrase. First of all, we have a gym. What do you do at a gym, Marco?
好的。这是一个非常重要的短语，要记住。首先，我们有“健身房”。你在健身房做什么，Marco？
Well, you work out.
嗯，你锻炼身体。
Yeah. You exercise. Maybe you run on the treadmill or you lift weights.
是的。你运动。也许你在跑步机上跑步，或者举重。
But it's important to remember that the verb here is to go to the gym.
但重要的是要记住，这里的动词是“去健身房”。
So I could say I go to the gym three times a week. How often do you go to the gym?
所以我可以说我每周去健身房三次。你多久去一次健身房？
Okay. So that's the phrase. You go to the gym.
好的。这就是这个短语。你去健身房。
I stop going to the gym and I gain a little weight.
我不去健身房了，就胖了一点。
Okay. So that's the way you use it. You don't use any other verb when you're talking about the gym. You say you go to the gym.
好的。这就是它的用法。当你谈论健身房时，不要用其他动词。你说“去健身房”。
I go to the gym. He goes to the gym regularly.
我去健身房。他定期去健身房。
All right. Very good. So that's all the Fluency Builder for today. Let's review our dialogue one last time.
好的。非常好。这就是今天的流利度训练。让我们最后复习一遍对话。
Hey, honey. Where were you?
嘿，亲爱的。你去哪儿了？
I decided to take Kenny to the park and get some fresh air.
我决定带肯尼去公园呼吸点新鲜空气。
How was it? Were there a lot of kids?
怎么样？孩子多吗？
It wasn't too crowded, but we had a great time.
不太拥挤，但我们玩得很开心。
We got on the seesaw together, then went on a couple of different slides, and then I tried to go with him in the jungle gym, but I didn't fit.
我们一起玩跷跷板，然后滑了几个不同的滑梯，接着我想和他一起进攀爬架，但我进不去。
Sounds like fun. When we go, he always just likes to play in the sandbox.
听起来很有趣。我们去的时候，他总是只喜欢在沙坑里玩。
Yeah, but today he was really hyper. He even got under the monkey bars.
是啊，但今天他特别兴奋。他甚至钻到了猴架下面。
And then he went on to go on the swings for half an hour. I'm exhausted.
然后他又去荡了半小时秋千。我累坏了。
You should go to the park more often since you don't go to the gym anymore.
你应该多去公园，反正你也不去健身房了。
All right. So growing up, there are many, many different games at parks that you can probably find, especially now you have such great playground equipment.
好的。所以从小到大，公园里有很多很多不同的游戏可以玩，尤其是现在有这么多好玩的游乐设施。
But I think these are the most basic ones that everyone knows about.
但我觉得这些是大家最熟悉的基本项目。
That's right. These are pretty standard things that you'll see at a playground.
没错。这些是你在游乐场会看到的很标准的东西。
Remember that a park doesn't have to have these things.
记住，公园不一定有这些东西。
Parks are just public places, maybe with benches and trees.
公园只是公共场所，可能只有长椅和树木。
But a playground is the part of the park where you'll see these kinds of things like a slide or swings.
但游乐场是公园的一部分，你会看到像滑梯或秋千这样的东西。
And so it's important to remember that they're not the same.
所以记住它们不一样很重要。
Right. And now, did you ever have a bad accident or did you fall off the swing or the seesaw or maybe you fell off the slide?
对。那么，你有没有出过严重事故？或者从秋千、跷跷板、滑梯上摔下来过？
Oh, I fell all the time.
哦，我经常摔。
Never a serious accident, but swings, I liked to swing.
从没出过严重事故，但秋千，我喜欢荡秋千。
And when I was forward, you know, up in the air, I used to let go and jump.
当我荡到前面，你知道，在空中时，我常常放手跳下来。
You would jump off the swing.
你会从秋千上跳下来。
I would jump off the swing. So when you're very high in the air, it feels like you're flying for a minute.
我会从秋千上跳下来。所以当你荡得很高时，感觉就像飞了一会儿。
My mother hated it because she thought I was going to break my arms.
我妈妈很讨厌这样，因为她觉得我会摔断胳膊。
But I loved it.
但我很喜欢。
It's great fun. And actually, we would really like to know, maybe you have some pictures that you can share with us of some specific playground equipment that we may have missed.
非常好玩。实际上，我们很想知道，也许你有照片可以分享给我们，展示一些我们可能遗漏的特定游乐设施。
There are a lot of things out there and maybe locally there are even some more fun things that we don't have.
外面有很多东西，也许当地还有一些我们这里没有的更有趣的东西。
So let us know what do playgrounds look like in your country.
所以告诉我们，你们国家的游乐场是什么样的。
We hope to see you at EnglishPod.com.
我们希望在EnglishPod.com上见到你。
All right. We'll see you guys there.
好的。我们那里见。
Bye.
再见。